Personal Website

# MOAMEN ZAHER



Egypt https://moamenzaher.github.io moamen.zaher@icloud.com www.linkedin.com/in/moamenzaher ORCID: 0009-0004-8560-4563

Master's student specialized in Human-Computer Interaction (HCI) with several <u>published</u> research papers in both journals and conferences. I'm also an experienced Teaching Assistant with 4 years of instructing diverse Software Engineering courses, including Web development, Object-Oriented programming, Machine learning, HCI, Service-Oriented Architecture and more. Also, worked as a Senior Software Engineer for 3 years, bringing practical market experience.

### **EXPERIENCE**

MAR 2020 - NOW

P

#### TEACHING ASSISTANT, MODERN SCIENCES AND ARTS (MSA) UNIVERSITY, EGYPT

Instructed a variety of Software Engineering courses, offering guidance to senior-level students during their capstone projects. Contributed actively to numerous interdisciplinary initiatives and collaborations.

Instructed a variety of Software Engineering courses including data structures, mobile programming and OOP in addition to guidance to

OCT 2023 - NOW

TEACHING ASSISTANT, ESLSCA UNIVERSITY, EGYPT

senior-level students during their capstone projects.

MAR 2021 - SENIOR SOFTWARE ENGINEER , ISTUDY

DEC 2023

Developing Various API Services.

AUG 2016 - TRAINEE, VODAFONE SEP 2017

FEB 2017 -Mar 2017 TRAINEE, TECHNOLOGY INNOVATION AND ENTREPRENEURSHIP CENTER (TIEC).

## **EDUCATION**

NOV 2020 -NOW

JUN 2014 -JUN 2018 M.SC. COMPUTER SCIENCE, HELWAN UNIVERSITY – CAIRO

Collaborated on a project focusing on integrating human activity recognition techniques into physical rehabilitation.

BA.SC. COMPUTER SCIENCE, HELWAN UNIVERSITY – CAIRD

Department of Software Engineering, GPA: 3.2

## **PUBLICATIONS**

- Zaher, M., Ghoneim, A. S., Abdelhamid, L., & Atia, A. (2024). Unlocking the potential of RNN and CNN models for accurate rehabilitation exercise classification on multi-datasets. Multimedia Tools and Applications. <a href="https://doi.org/10.1007/s11042-024-19092-0">https://doi.org/10.1007/s11042-024-19092-0</a>
- Zaher, M., Samir, A., Ghoneim, A., Abdelhamid, L., & Atia, A. (2023, July). A Framework for Assessing Physical Rehabilitation Exercises. In 2023 Intelligent Methods, Systems, and Applications (IMSA) (pp. 526-532). IEEE. <a href="https://doi.org/10.1109/IMSA58542.2023.10217392">https://doi.org/10.1109/IMSA58542.2023.10217392</a>
- Walid, M., Ameen, M., Zaher, M., & Atia, A. (2024, March). A Scoring Approach for Improving Presentation Impact: Addressing Voice Stuttering, AR Glasses-Based Emotion Recognition, and Profiled Movement Assessment. In 2024 6th International Conference on Computing and Informatics (ICCI) (pp. 284-290). IEEE. <a href="https://doi.org/10.1109/ICCI61671.2024.10485076">https://doi.org/10.1109/ICCI61671.2024.10485076</a>
- Amgad, N., Ahmed, M., Haitham, H., Zaher, M., & Mohammed, A. (2023, July). A Robust Ensemble Deep Learning Approach for Breast Cancer Diagnosis. In 2023 Intelligent Methods, Systems, and Applications (IMSA) (pp. 452-457). IEEE. <a href="https://doi.org/10.1109/IMSA58542.2023.10217501">https://doi.org/10.1109/IMSA58542.2023.10217501</a>

# CERTIFICATIONS

- DeepLearning.Al: Structuring Machine Learning Projects April 2024
- DeepLearning.Al: Hyperparameter Tunning, Regularization, and Optimization April 2024
- DeepLearning.Al: Neural Networks and Deep Learning April 2024
- 4 AWS Badges: Introduction to Cloud 101 and Getting Started with (Computer, Storage, and Networking).
- Microsoft Certified: Azure Al Fundamentals 22 Aug 2021.

#### **ZKILL** 2

- Deep understanding of Applying OOP principles to develop modular, maintainable, and scalable software solutions in Java, php, Python and C#.
- Skilled in machine learning workflows, utilizing TensorFlow and scikit-learn to create and deploy AI models for diverse tasks such as classification and HAR. Familiarity with Unity.
- Experienced in image analysis with OpenCV, adept at preprocessing, feature extraction, object detection, AR, and deploying deep learning models for image-related tasks.
- Proficient in full-stack web development, utilizing different stacks such as LAMP. Skilled in building RESTful APIs and integrating third-party services for seamless user experiences.